He's somebody that plays with what I
like to call a battery pack in his back
and it never loses any notches in the
percentage as far as how he plays. Are
we about to see an early run on edge
rushers in the NFL draft? ESPN draft
analyst Jordan Reed tells us why it
could happen. We'll build the perfect
linebacker. Jordan will also make a case
[music] for a trade up for the Jets in
round one and will deliver a special
two-round mock draft. Now boarding
begins in three, two, one.
Let's bring in ESPN NFL draft analyst
Jordan Reed. Jordan, so great to see you
once again.
How big of an opportunity is this for
the New York Jets to bring in some
building blocks for this franchise
considering their draft capital over the
next two years? 19 picks in all,
five in the first round over the next
two drafts and eight in the first and
second rounds combined.
Well, it's huge. Whenever you have that
amount of draft capital, it creates
flexibility, which is what Aaron Glenn
and Darren Moji want just because you're
attempting to lay the foundation of this
Jets roster that has already started
bringing in a ton of better
agency already. So now you want to
sprinkle in those young players now they
have a lot of opportunities with four
picks in the first 44 picks. Excuse me,
four picks inside of the first 44 picks,
you have an opportunity to really lay
the foundation of these players. Do you
anticipate a run
on edges there at the top of the draft
because the consensus right now,
Fernando Mendoza out of Indiana goes one
to the Raiders. Could we see edges go
two, three, four?
I think we could and you talk about
somebody like Arval Reese out of Ohio
State and even David Bailey out of Texas
Tech and also Ruben Bain out of Miami. I
think those are your clear three edge
rushers that could go off of the board
consecutively. Now it's going to be
really interesting to see which one the
Jets do take at two. There's a clear
need for them to rush the passer and
whether it's Reese, Bailey, or Bain,
they're going to have an opportunity to
really continue to lay that foundation
with a foundational piece with any one
of those three players. Great transition
right there. The Jets sitting there at
number two overall. Uh let's do wheels
up, wheels down as far as stock is
concerned because in a previous mock
draft, you actually had the Jets taking
Ruben Bain, but in your latest, you had
the Jets taking Arval Reese. So I would
imagine in your eyes his stock is up.
Absolutely. I mean, you talk about
somebody at 6'5, 244 lb. He was
everything for that Ohio State defense
this past season. You could put him at
off-ball linebacker, you could put him
at edge rusher. He's that
jack-of-all-trades
player that you can use on the second or
even the first level as well. I really
love how Matt Patricia used him this
last season. He was able to utilize all
those tools that he has. So for Darren
Moji and Aaron Glenn, I think they're
going to fall in love with the skillset
of what he has presently, but also what
he can be in the future as well. I got
to give you a lot of credit because from
the get-go, you've always liked Ruben
Bain, but in your eyes for the Jets, is
his stock falling just a little bit?
Just a little bit just because there's
more question marks with him just
because of the arm length and then he's
just not as crafty of a fast rusher like
a David Bailey, but I think he's more
versatile than the other two in my
opinion from a run game perspective and
then also how he does rush the passer,
but I think it's going to be between
David Bailey and Arval Reese at the top
of the draft. I still personally believe
that Ruben Bain is the best edge rusher
in this year's draft just because I have
David Bailey as an off-ball linebacker.
That's where I believe he should start
out personally, but Ruben Bain, if they
do select him at two, I'm not going to
blink an eye or complain at all,
honestly. Where do you stand on Bailey
right now? Is he the best Does he have
the best technique of all the guys
coming out right at this point?
From just a pass rush perspective, he
obviously is the most productive and you
talk about explosiveness out of the
starting blocks. I think he's clearly
better than the other two in that facet.
He still needs to improve a little bit
as far as the consistency as a run
defender, but I mean, 14 and a half
sacks last year, the production speaks
for itself. 19 and a half tackles for
loss this past season as well. So he's
able to get after the quarterback, but
he doesn't only create a pressure, but
there's a lot of other things that he
can do as well. That's why I think if
they want somebody that can contribute
right away as far as being a 10-plus
sack guy even early on as a rookie, I
think David Bailey can be that right
away. Quickly on the quarterbacks, we
talked about Mendoza just a little bit
before. Where do you stand on the gap
between him and Ty Simpson?
I think Mendoza is the clear one in this
year's class. He's my undeniable
quarterback one at this spot, but Ty
Simpson, he got much better early on in
the season. Had a little bit of
precipitous drop-off at the end,
injuries, a lack of run game as well,
but that eight-game stretch of where he
showed 19 touchdowns, only one
interception, a little over 1,700
passing yards as well. He was able to do
a lot of things and show a lot of
things. Even though he's only a 15-game
career starter, I think there's a lot of
things to really be intrigued about with
Ty from a skillset perspective. This is
something that we like to call gate
change as far as movement is concerned.
For a while now, you've had the Jets
looking to move up. We talked to Indy
and he said potentially maybe go after a
Caleb Downs, but also you've talked
about potentially maybe getting a guy
like Mekhi Leven. Do you think it makes
a lot of sense for the Jets as far as
your first round grades are concerned to
get out of that 16 spot and go up?
I think that's the great thing and goes
back to the flexibility that I talked
about early on when we were talking. You
have 16, you have 33, and you have 44 as
well. So if somebody like a Mekhi Leven
gets to 12 or 13 or even a Jordan
Addison or Carnell Tate, if one of those
receivers starts to get in that early
teens area, you have two really early
second round picks that could really
entice a team to potentially trade back.
So just imagine Mekhi Leven or Jordan
Addison paired with Garrett Wilson. Now
you're talking about a dynamic one-two
punch. Do you think one of those three
make the most sense as a compliment for
the Jets when you're talking about a guy
like Wilson?
I think Garrett Wilson is so good, it
doesn't really matter who you have as a
number two behind him, but if I had to
pick one player to be that number two
behind him, it would be Mekhi Leven just
because of the slot versatility that he
has and I think he can play on the
outside as well, but I just think it
unlocks another dimension and unlocks
another chapter to the playbook as well
when you can have somebody that can play
outside as well as inside equally as
good. So that's why I keep mocking Mekhi
Leven to the Jets just because I think
it's such a good fit behind Garrett
Wilson as that certified wide receiver
two. Jordan, let's build a perfect
linebacker from this 2026 class using
the following five traits: intelligence,
football IQ, tackling ability, speed,
coverage ability, and motor. So you know
this group quite well. Who would you go
to as far as intelligence, football IQ?
Oh, that's a great question. I would go
with Jacob Rodriguez out of Texas Tech.
Somebody that is very instinctive. He
understands run schemes. You saw, I
mean, he was nominated and won pretty
much every accolade that he was up for
this past season and then just how smart
he is as a second level defender. I
think he's going to be a really, really
good pro. What about coverage ability?
Coverage ability,
I would go with Sunny Styles in that
area just because I mean, somebody that
is a former safety, he transitioned to
that off-ball linebacker spot and there
was no drop-off at all with him. He's so
instinctive in coverage. He can really
recognize route concepts as well. So I
would go with Sunny Styles in that area.
How about tackling?
Am I able to use the same answer twice
because I probably would go with Sunny
Styles, but I'll give you a different
answer. I'll go with C.J. Allen out of
Georgia for that one. Somebody that's a
wrap-up finish and very violent tackler
when he's stepping downhill. So he's
somebody I think potentially could go in
that back end of the first round as
well, but somebody that is a very
violent tackler and can come up and
finish ball carriers at the point of
attack, I would go with C.J. Allen. How
about speed? You know everybody wants a
linebacker who can get sideline to
sideline.
Let's go with um
I'm going to cheat here. I'm I have
Arval Reese as an off-ball linebacker,
so I'm going to use Arval Reese in this
situation. He has that sideline-sideline
ability. There isn't anything that gets
outside of his range when he is playing
that off-ball linebacker spot. So Arval
Reese would be my contender in this
spot.
How about motor? You want a guy who
never shuts off, who's always got that
green light and always on go.
That's an easy one for me. It'd be
Anthony Hill out of Texas. He's somebody
that plays with what I like to call a
battery pack in his back and it never
loses any notches in the percentage as
far as how he plays. He's playing full
go at every single opportunity that he
gets whether it's moving forward, moving
backward, playing against the run,
playing against the pass as well. So
Anthony Hill, he's another player that
is just full go at every single
opportunity. So real quickly, that would
be an awesome linebacker if you put all
those guys together in those traits.
Would you consider Styles at two at all
with the Jets? And let's say you don't,
here's part B the question.
Do you think Hill would be a
consideration at 33 if you keep that
pick?
Yeah, I think so. I think that's a great
question and I think this is the type of
draft of where you throw positional
value out of the window and we're seeing
guys like a Caleb Downs and Jeremiah
Love out of Notre Dame who I think are
the two best players in this year's
draft being considered as top-10 picks.
Just because of the lack of quarterbacks
and the lack of blue-chip talent at the
top of the draft, it makes sense to
consider somebody like a Sunny Styles at
number two overall. And if that's the
direction the Jets go, I wouldn't be
surprised by that at all. Just because
he's such a clean evaluation from the
tape that he put on this year, the
performance that he put on at the
combine, and then just the things that
he has been able to get better at
throughout the season. I think he's such
a clean evaluation, and you need that
player in the middle. Linebacker's a
huge question mark for the Jets right
now. So, getting that player in the
middle who I've compared to Fred Warner,
I don't think anybody's going to
complain about taking a Fred Warner type
of player at number two overall. Now, on
the inverse with Anthony Hill, he's
another player I think could be in
consideration at number 33 overall, and
I think this is a really good linebacker
class in general. So, somebody like
Anthony Hill that I think is a
plug-and-play player, whether it's at
middle linebacker or on the weak side, I
think you're getting a starter at number
33. If you do go the Anthony Hill route.
The Jets have needs at edge, cornerback,
receiver, maybe a young quarterback, and
offensive line interior. With that being
said, let's move to day three of the
draft. Can you give us a couple of
diamonds, maybe one offensive player and
one defensive player, who might make
sense for Darren Mougey in the green and
white?
So, I'll stick with the Jets needs. One
player that I think is a diamond in the
rough that deserves more love. His name
is Kevin Coleman. He's a wide receiver
from Missouri, and he's been
well-traveled, just like every other
player in college football it seems like
now. He's transferred three times. Um,
he was he actually originally started
his career at Jackson State. He was one
of Shedur Sanders' very first receivers
during their first year at Jackson
State. Um, ends up he finishes his
career at Missouri, was one of their
best targets a season ago. I think he
has to transition to the slot on the
next level, but very sure-handed, really
good route runner. He can run every
branch on the route tree. He can climb
the ladder and um, get those 50/50 balls
over those DBs as well. So, Kevin
Coleman definitely would be one player
that I definitely would consider. And
then another, if the Jets are looking
for a cornerback. Now, I think this guy
has to be a nickel on the next level,
but his name is Jayden Kennedy out of
Oregon. Another player that's very
instinctive, very physical, has really
good ball skills as well.
I like those. Uh, how about the
quarterback spot? Um, if the Jets don't
go early there, and they're looking to
take maybe not so much a flyer, but more
of a developmental prospect that you
like and it might make sense them
bringing him in the building.
Well, I don't know what how much time we
have, but as a former quarterback, I can
talk about these guys all day long,
especially the very underrated ones.
But, somebody that I think is that could
carve out a really long career is Luke
Altmyer out of Illinois. He's that
typical West Coast type of quarterback
that gets the ball out really quickly.
He's really decisive. He has experience
from shotgun and under center. I think
he sleep he sees the field really well,
and also he has a mobility factor to him
as well. So, if they're looking to take
somebody in the fifth or the sixth
round, and what I like to call lottery
tickets, if you're looking to cash in
potentially to get one of those
late-round lottery tickets, Luke Altmyer
out of Illinois is one name that I would
be heavily interested in. But, Jordan,
why has he been why is Luke been flying
under the radar a little bit?
I I think it's just because a lot of
people see the traits or lack thereof
with him, and that was a big reason why
like a Brock Purdy fell to the seventh
round. Whenever a guy doesn't have those
overwhelming traits, and then they don't
have a lot of um, year-to-year success
as far as putting up the gaudy stats,
they're going to be considered a
late-round player. But, I was really
impressed with him throughout the
season, then he goes on. I thought he
performed really well at the Senior Bowl
as well. He made some nice throws and
stacks, some really good days of
practices there as well. And he played
really good in the game as well. So, you
want to see those traits translate
especially into an NFL setting like
that, and I just think he's continued to
check every single box in the process.
All right, you've prepared for this
because you can wear the GM hat for 32
teams. Now, what I'm going to put the
hat on you for the Jets. You got Darren
Mougey's spot right now. We're going to
do a two-round mock draft with you.
Number two overall, who you taking?
I'm going to go with Arvell Reese out of
Ohio State, and I just think the upside
that he has and the potential that he
has, whether it's at off-ball linebacker
or edge rusher, these are the type of
foundational pieces, high-upside pieces
that you would love to take with the
Jets. And I just think he's just
scratching the surface of what he can
be. So, I would go with Arvell Reese at
number two overall. All right, I'm the
commissioner here in the mock draft, and
I say Jordan, you can make trades if you
want. The Jets do have the number 16
overall pick.
So, I'm actually going to uh, stay stand
pat here, and Mekhi Wingo is actually on
the board just because we're in a
hypothetical, and this is our own mock
draft, right? So, we make up the rules.
So, Mekhi Wingo is sitting there for me
at number 16 overall, and I'm running to
turn that card in. And I know we have to
wait um, for the clock to wind down a
little bit on draft day. I know you guys
hate that. You want the card to just be
turned in, but we're going to make your
job easy here, and we're going to turn
that card in within a minute of us being
on the clock, and I'm going to go with
Mekhi Wingo. I just think he's such a
great fit alongside Garrett Wilson, and
we want to set up um, this
infrastructure to where we eventually
can welcome in a quarterback. So, just
imagine an offensive infrastructure of
Olu Fashanu, Alim McNeill at our
offensive tackle spots, and then we have
Breece Hall in the backfield to
complement Mekhi Wingo as well as
Garrett Wilson. I think that's such a
great setup. All right, Jordan. It is
Thursday night. Night one is over, but
people are blowing up your phone. You
know they want that 33rd overall pick.
Are you sitting tight and taking
someone?
Yeah, I'm going to sit tight, and we're
going to take one of the better players
who could be available at the top of the
draft board. And one name I want Jets
fans to become very familiar with is AJ
Harris, who is a safety out of LSU.
He He's one of my favorite players in
this year's draft. You talk about
somebody that is an energizer bunny. He
brings that type of attitude and
intensity that you love to see at the
position. And I just love DBs that have
a little bit of trash talk to them. And
Harris is one of those players that has
a lot of confidence. He feels as if he's
the best player in the stadium, and it
doesn't matter who's in the stadium with
him, he's going to feel like he's the
best he's the best player there. So, I'm
going to go with AJ Harris at number 33
overall. Jets certainly need more
takeaways in 2026, and Harris
showed a propensity for that on the
collegiate level. How about number 44
overall?
I'm actually going to go corner here. I
think the Jets could use another corner.
So, I'm going to go with Brandon Ceaser,
who's a corner out of South Carolina.
Once again, I don't know if he's going
to be here, but this is our mock draft,
we make up the rules. Uh, Brandon Ceaser
is one player that I'm a big fan of.
More athlete than technician right now,
but once again, these are the
high-upside players that you have time
um, to really bank on if you're the
Jets. Didn't have any interceptions last
season, so he's going to bring some ball
production along with him. So, Brandon
Ceaser out of South Carolina, I I think
he would be a great fit at 44. Finally,
Jordan, we're throwing you the virtual
whiteboard. You are in the Jets draft
room right now. You are a scout, and
they're asking you your red star player.
Who you standing up for and saying,
"This is the guy we need."
So, just
not basing this on the Jets needs, but
just in general, one player that I love
is Caleb Downs out of Ohio State. I
think he's just such a clean evaluation.
He's one of the smartest safeties that
I've ever evaluated, and it's very rare
to see a player have such [snorts] the
high quality of success that he had at
two blue-blood programs at Alabama, and
then transitioning onto Ohio State. Very
sure tackler, he has the ball production
that you love to see at the position as
well. The player that I compare him to
is Budda Baker. We saw Budda Baker,
who's going on to be a multi-time
all-pro player in Arizona. You can use
him in so many different ways. So, I
think Aaron Glenn would be really
excited to use him in so many different
ways. So, Caleb Downs would be my red
star player.
Jordan, thanks for playing Jets GM just
for a day. We're going to continue
[music] to follow you, of course, and
all your pre-draft analysis on ESPN.
[music] Thanks so much.
Thank you for having me as always.